Jose Mari Ponce



linkedin.com/in/ecnopdev



https://ecnop.dev



ponce_josemari@yahoo.com



94684121

Summary

Australian Permanent Resident subclass 189.

Specialties: VueJS, NodeJS, Php, GSuite, Google Cloud, Firebase, SCRUM

Solutions developer with substantial software development experience specializing in web and mobile business applications. Handled projects concentrate mainly on work-flows (HR Applications, Document Tracking Systems, etc) and computation-extensive algorithms (Accounting, Financial and Content Management). Particularly interested in full-stack web development using VueJS, NodeJS, Firebase and Google Cloud. Always interested in working with teams, as well as exploring new development methodologies.

Experience



sph Software Engineer

Singapore Press Holdings

Sep 2014 - Present (5 years 10 months +)

Design, develop, and implement enterprise applications using Google Cloud, VueJS, NodeJS, Firebase, GSuite, and Php.



Software Engineer

Orica

Jul 2013 - Aug 2014 (1 year 2 months)

- Design, develop and implement business applications using various technologies (Lotus Notes Xpages and Java)
- Gather requirements from clients and convert high-level requirements to technical specifications
- Author detailed technical designs and implementation strategies
- Provides level 2 and level 3 production support to end-users of Orica world-wide.
- Execute test plans and quality assurance tasks during development.

Systems Analyst

Sun Life

Dec 2011 - Jul 2013 (1 year 8 months)

- Design, develop and implement business applications using various technologies (Lotus Notes and Java)
- Gather requirements from clients and convert high-level requirements to technical specifications
- Author detailed technical designs and implementation strategies
- Provide production support to end-users in Hong Kong, Indonesia, Vietnam and Philippines
- Execute test plans and quality assurance tasks during development.

Software Engineer

Abbott

Aug 2011 - Dec 2011 (5 months)

Develop and enhance business applications using Lotus Notes



Software Engineer

Softweb Consulting Inc

Feb 2008 - Aug 2011 (3 years 7 months)

Sr. Lotus Notes developer specializing in Lotus Notes and Xpages application development. (Domino and LN version 7/8/8.5.1/8.5.2); A Lotus Notes Database Programmer provides database design, development and management support and has a knowledge and understanding of applicable technical concepts and practices.

■ Team Lead

Softweb Consulting Inc

Jul 2009 - Jul 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Facilitates projects using agile development methodologies (SCRUM). Also participates in application design and development.

Php Developer

Softweb Consulting Inc

Feb 2008 - Jul 2011 (3 years 6 months)

Develops open-source applications using Codeigniter(Php) and Doctrine(MySQL)

Junior Php Developer

Optimind Solutionz

Apr 2006 - Jun 2006 (3 months)

Develops a web-based retirement application for the Armed Forces of the Philippines.

Education



📆 De La Salle University

Bachelor of Science degree, Computer Science; Software Technology 2004 - 2008

University of the Philippines

Master of Information Systems, Information Technology

2019 - 2022

Don Bosco Technical Institute

Computer Technology Class

2000 - 2004

Don Bosco Technical Institute

High School Diploma

1993 - 2000

Licenses & Certifications



Certified Scrum Master - Scrum Alliance



Google Cloud: Getting Started With Application Development - Coursera

ZTVR2KHQZ3R2



HTML/CSS and Vue.js (Hard) - TestDome

Issued Nov 2019 - Expires Nov 2022 5a39e4da7ab14b74b00aaf8e779ecfc6



Vue.is - TestDome

Issued Nov 2019 - Expires Nov 2022

b98adf279bcb425395c4ab581c2cae99

- WHITE BELT Certifed Secure Developer Secure Code Warrior kssjmpv1@sph.com.sg
- Cloud Hero: Application Development Qwiklabs
- Octoud Hero: Core Infrastructure Qwiklabs
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera
- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation Coursera
 5B3OEMV2WHGS
- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Coursera
 9GMGLQ9VG42A
- Elastic Google Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation Coursera
 U9VB42RYOJ89
- Reliable Google Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process Coursera
 99SZ99X9LG83
- Cloud Architecture with Google Cloud Specialization Coursera
 AJC3S8D7XR95
- Securing and Integrating Components of your Application Coursera GRZVNBNJBDAU
- **Developing Applications with Google Cloud Platform Specialization** Coursera A7WWUXKQZQA8
- Cloud Engineering with Google Cloud Specialization Coursera
 73HXKFDBFA48

Skills

JavaScript • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Node.js • Scrum • Software Development • Web Applications • Agile Project Management • Web Development • Agile Methodologies • Systems Analysis